Sandeep Choudhary gmail@sandeepk.dev blog.sandeepk.dev www.sandeepk.dev +91 7289993532

Sandeep Choudhary

About Me Result-driven software engineer with 4 years of experience working in high-paced startups across Frontend, Backend, and DevOps. I take great interest in working across different teams, solving problems, and carrying out research for utilizing the best of the technology.

Experience

June 2017 - present, Core Team Member | Software Engineer II, FCB Technologies

Joined as the first employee outside the exec team. Involved in various efforts for growth of the company.

- Achieve 20% more usage of the product by improving Chrome app, which became a great selling point.
- Implement AGILE METHODOLOGIES in the development process and completed 30+ sprints successfully, resulting in more customer satisfaction and faster growth towards PRODUCT MARKET FIT.
- Automate manual task for sales and operations team. [Similarity System, Scrapper, Smoothing On-boarding tasks].
- Achieve better analysis of the system usage by integrating different services.[Amplitude, Postmark, Google Analytics and Optimize].
- Reduce business report generation time by 80%, which helps the user to take a data-driven decision faster.
- Initiate the process of system migration from Python 2.7 to Python 3.x.

Jan 2017 - June 2017, Software Engineer Trainee, CEBS Worldwide

• Reduce the manual work of Inventory sync by implementing the RESTful APIs to sync data from market places (Amazon).

Dec 2016 - Jan 2017, Software Engineer Intern, FCB Technologies

- Build Business Intelligence screen for overall insights of the transactions to achieve more user engagement.
- Implement the data validation across the web-app.

Education

2013 - 2017, Amritsar College of Engineering & Technology B.Tech in Computer Science (80%)

Skills

Backend: Python(Django, Django Rest Framework) **Frontend:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript (jQuery, Vue.js)

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Misc: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Git

Conferences & Volunteer Experience

- Volunteer at FOSDEM 2021(Online)
- Attendee at PyCon India 2020(Online)
- Volunteer at PyCon India 2019(Chennai),
- Volunteer at PyCon India 2018(Hyderbad)
- Attendee at PyCon India 2017(Delhi)



Blog QR code